<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" rendition="tei:teisimple">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
<p>Mrs. Hanson, the daughter is a widow employed in the Handcrafted Department of the WPA, and the son, Reed, plays a violin in a local orchestra.</p>
<p>May 19, 1939.</p>
<p>John Reese (colored, 59 farmer</p>
<p>Morris Reese (colored, 77 Farmer</p>
<p>Mulberry Grove Plantation Yukon, Florida.</p>
<p>Rose Shepherd, Writer</p>
<p>JOHN REESE and RIS FOORE</p>
<p>These men were interviewed together to their remembrances of life on the A. M. Rood "Mulberry Grove Plantation." and early history of the Yukon section.</p>
<p>REESES: "I am the son of Joe Reese, the youngest of ten children. Our home was at Black Point, on the exact spot where Dr. c. w. Zaring has lately built his house. I am  years old and have lived all my life in this section.  'big house' where the Reed family lived faced the . Johns River, about three hundred feet from the water. t back of it was the smokehouse made of tabby-oysterl and lime-and the brick kitchen where the cooking was done. All food was prepared here, put on big trays, and carried along the brick walk to the big house, where it was ved. The lower part of the old kitchen is still .</p>
<p>"The old road which went by the side of the first rail road tracks, went past the old plantation and my father's home, connecting Ortega and Orange Park. In some places the road was two miles from the river, in others only about half a mile. This old road to Orange Park is considerably  of here (Woods' Garage and filling station on the Yukon Highway).</p>
<p>"When I could first remember, there were two rows of oaks, overlapping overhear, which made a shady walk from the plantation house to the dock at the river. Those trees were set out after emancipation by a negro man. John Be, a fisherman, who made his living catching fish in the river and selling them to settlers of the section. There were a few mulberry trees standing in scattered sections around the house - big trees.</p>
<p>"I would say about 900 of the 1,400 acres of the plantation was in cultivation. No cotton was raised in my time t everything else that could be planted and grown on a farm was raised at mulberry Grove-corn, sugarcane, peas, beans, cats, potatoes- both sweet and white - cabbage, all kinds of garden vegetables. Mr. Rood had a big strawberry  and there were fruit trees - pears, plums and peaches - and a big orange grove surrounded the house and lay to the east between the house and the river. Oranges were picked, crated, and shipped out on the river steamboats in considerable quantities. Always around fifty men were hired to take care of the extra work at this section. There were no slaves-everybody was paid by the day- field hands and heavy work. 50 aday, and lighter work 40.</p>
<p>"The negroes all bought homes in the neighborhood, and being employees of Mr. Rood they had a good chance of paying for the land bought from him.</p>
<p>"My father, Joe Reese, bought 20 acres on Black paint - the exact spot nrivatoly owned by Mr. Baring. After my mother and father , some of us children always lived in the old house. We all worked for Mr. . When I was a little shaver and up to the time I was 15 years old I ran errands and out firewood and carried it to the kitchen, for cooking, and to the big house for the  and hurting stoves.</p>
<p>"In 1910 I went over to Ortega to work for  who was laying out the old Sadler point plantation in building lots, cutting streets and putting in sidewalks. I worked there twelve years, thon in 1922 went to Philadelphia, doing and john for three years. I got homesick for my brothers and sisters. They seemed to know it, and played a trick on go to get me back home - told me the roof was falling in on father's old house. I rushed home to found everything in good shape, and they laughed at the joke, but I guess they wanted to see mo as bad as I did them. So I was back to stay, and an never going away again.</p>
<p>"I bought my own place, sixty acres, and built me house - you can see it right on the corner yonder on the  side of the road. I get work around. And I raise my own vegetables and chickens, and get along all right. I have never fussed or fought, and have never been in any trouble.</p>
<p>"I do not know how they come to name this place 'Yukon." It had been called that ever since the Atlantic Coast nine Railroad was put through here."</p>
<p>At this time MORRIE REESE </p>
<p>"This here section was  called Black point, bat the railroad people wanted a  name - a word with four letters. So they just took 'Yukon.' No, I don't know why - they just wanted a short .</p>
<p>"The first postmaster was J. J. knight. No lives in green cove springs. No has been in the  but he's all right now. He has a brother and sister living at , and if you can't  him, they'll tell you where he is.</p>
<p>"I was born at Sadier's point (Ortega) in 1862. My  refugeed to , Florida, during the war between the , and I was a babe in arms at that time.</p>
<p>The old Sadler house was on the point of at. Johns after, where the big brick house now is (The George ) when Mr. Stockton took ever the plantation - it was five thousand acres - the original home which was a big frame house, was taken down.</p>
<p>"We case back in 1869, and is and my folks have been in this section ever since. We have always worked for ourselves.</p>
<p>"I remember Mr. Reed and the old Road plantation of Mulberry Grove. A man by the name of C. D. Brigham came down from the north and bought 500 acres of it. He raised lots and lows of sugarcane and corn. I do not remember when or who he left. He put in a sawmill after he took over the place  he always raised large lots of hogs, too.</p>
<p>"His house was on the road to the docks. He was hope in the 1870's and stayed about ten years. The land  bought was originally a part of the old Mulberry Grove Plantation. The land was along the river, and did not come up to this road."</p>
<p>REESE: "Where were the old slave quarters? Well, they were a row of house on a road back of the big house - about twenty-five family houses - and it was just like a little town, with a street in the middle and houses on each side,  all built long before the war.</p>
<p>"The Reeds were all good to us, it was a nice place,  of work, and plenty to oat - it was the nicest place I've ever worked.</p>
<p>"Reed Person, Mr. Reed's grandson, was such older than - he was my foreman, when I worked in the fields."</p>
<p>MOORE: Mr. A. M. reed was a small man, rather stout Reed Pearson was about age.</p>
<p>REESE: "The church is in the same place it has always , just beyond the road here. In times of slavery, the  people did not have the privileges they do now. There were morning prayers in the big house in the dining room, but the time of our won churches came later.</p>
<p>" you hears negro hymns and spirituals - here is one I like:</p>
<p>"I heard the voice  saying,</p>
<p>'Come unto Me and rest,'</p>
<p>Soldier of the cross</p>
<p>In the fountain of the Lamb.' "</p>
<p>"In certain times of the spring and summer we used to have all-day "sings," but these have gene out of style in Florida, although they still have them in Georgia.</p>
<p>"When we were youngsters we used to have great running baseball and catball.</p>
<p>"No, we did not ho swimming - I was nearly grown before I learned to swim. Why? Alligators! You see my father's house was between two creeks - the nearest one about two hundred yards away - and they were always alive with alligators. They seemed to have some regard for elder people but for the little children, it just wouldn't do to lot from not too close to the water's edge - they'd be snapped  in a second. I remember their dreadful rearing at night - was awfully seared of them. Some of us older boys used to throw good sized logs at them - bigger around than my arm, and their terrible jaws would clamp down and crush them in two in a split second.</p>
<p>"My father was in a colored regiment during the war, and after it was ever he brought his old army musket home. The alligators were terrible about catching father's hogs.  he would hear a hog again  either of  crocks, he would grab the old musket and light out in the direction of the noise, and bang away with the gun, often killing the alligator with the hog in its mouth. Some of them oaid be ten or twelve f long. You don't see big , like you used to.</p>
<p>"When we used to join the river, we would bring the  up and empty the catfish on the bank -  body would eat catfish in those days, sometimes there would be ten  of them, and the  would climb up on the banks and have a feast. I have seen them,  big once, by the dozen,  catfish.</p>
<p>"In the old days there were door and wildcats in  woods, and the teens were so bad and there were so  them you could hardly raise corn or watermelons. They would  off the green corn and nibble it, like somebody going in rings around a !</p>
<p>"And watermelons - they would pick a nice ripe one, dig a hole through the rind, but in their saw and scrape out the  heart and eat it by the handful. If it was a big one around and dig in from the other. When we say a melon the  had 'Plugged,' we just left it alone, as we know it was  but an empty shell. Did they thump it? I don't know, but I do know that no  ever dug into a green watermelon."</p>
<p>MOORE: "They used to be the moistest snakes - moccasins , blacksnakes - they need to be so bad you could hardly walk for them along the creeks. One morning I was coming to work about six o'clock and had to  - I saw a lot of  counted twenty-five snakes stacked up on that leg. He,  my mind and went they up the creek and crossed on another leg.</p>
<p>", I don't remember having .  either in this section or Mandarin. But I do remember General Grant on the steamboat Water  coming up the river past the plantation - it was a side-wheeler, the stern-wheel are came afterwards.</p>
<p>"at did he look like. He looked all right - he was a rather small, red-headed man.</p>
<p>"I also remember the John Sylvester. The last time I went up the river to Palatka, I went on this boat."</p>
<p>"The Vigilant succeeded the John Sylvester on this . It was the largest of the propeller type boats -  screw just like the Clyde Line ships. And fast; My, she  eat through the water! She could out-race the  Sylvester. Then there was the city of Jacksonville -  but not so fast, and the Southern Belle.</p>
<p>"Sometimes the City of Jacksonville would come up the river and  up at Mr. Reed's docks, and they would have the grand parties, with dancing on the boat. They always had  orchestras.</p>
<p>"A lot of the produce from the plantation was shipped in Jacksonville or Sanford, and we had to put out a flag to  the  stop to take on this freight.</p>
<p>"One of our delights, too, was the sailboat and  races on the river, at  when we were not busy. Each fun, and such , and he the white folks would bet!</p>
<p>"Mr. Rood had ton rules and eight horses which he used to plow the ground for farming. When there were the carriage horses which were not used in the fields, and a few others for riding purposes. About fifty man were kept busy at the  of the season. All were hired by the day, and lived in the settlement around Black Point.</p>
<p>"My father, Joe Reese, had bargained for his twenty-fore home place and had paid a good deal on it. When the war  along. He joined the union forces, and after the coss of the war, he came back and started in just where he  off, planting his own garden, raising hogs, chickens, and turkeys, and we also had a cow. Mother used to buy goods by the yard and made our clothing an best she could. And we all worked and earned money and sent to Jacksonville for our shoes, coats, and caps. We went to school at Yukon.</p>
<p>"There were a lot of pecan trees around Mr. Rood's come of the old trunks still standing. They had the nicest uts - but they are like everything else, you have to culture whom if you went them to boar good.</p>
<p>"The sugar-house was up near the old 160-acre out field. This had a furnace with big  where the cane juice was boiled boiled down into syrup or molasses, as we know it, and some of the big vats were left to evaporate into sugar. They used to make sugar by the barrel and sell it. It was brown sugar, of course, as they know nothing about refining it.</p>
<p>"The dairy house  other way, in a line with the house and laundry.  the milk was kept, and to  for charming.</p>
<p>"Mr. Reed usually kept about hundred head of castle in the  - that was  live hundred  ration. He had lots of cows, and sold castle for  slaughtered some for use on the fa The meat which could not be taken care of immediately was smoked. ogs butchered and the neat  down."</p>
<p>"I remember they did make some attempt we know  The grain was thrashed out  made on of a round stamp with the center burned out, and  with a heavy wooden pestle. No, I don't know how  bread from rice flour."</p>
<p>"My mother used to gather herbs and room to doctor the family. There was a great deal of  and  I never remember her using the palmetto berries, but she did have what was called Jerusalem Oak - a wood that grows wild in the fields - and Black Root - both of which  steeped and made into teas for curing fever.  -bean leaves to cool the head, tying tge  around the head of a fever patient. Another  'life-overlasting' because it was always green, was dead or fevers. But after patent medicines came in those old home remedical  used.</p>
<p>"We need to  the river in bears, the overland nearly everybody by on."</p>
<p>"I used to like to hunt in the early days. There was plenty of wild game - , bears, duels,  You could shoot into a flock of wild down of the river and kill ton or twelve with  of backshot.</p>
<p>"The last time I want bear hunting  men and a passel of dogs,  by ten o'clock that right we had cornered and killed two bears - measuring seven feet from tip to tip.</p>
<p>"I saw one of then  for me, about forty feet away - I happened to be away from the crowd - and I sure aimed good, for I know it was either my life or his. He  once or twice after I shot him. There's one thing about killing a bear - you've act to kill him dead, because if he's only wounded, if  him had, and he'll tear up a human being or a dog that gets within his reach.</p>
<p>"One of the men who shot the other one, it fell, he  ever, but the bear got up and started after him, and  had to skin up a small tree in a hurry. And it's a good thing he picked a small tree. Because if he'd taken a big one, the bear would have  right up after him. Yes,  a wounded bear is a  follow.</p>
<p>The one I killed, I had to get down on my hands and  I located him, and crawl along, the brush was so I would have been scared, but I know I could depend upon my gun.</p>
<p>"We divided up the took the kind log of the one I killed, but I do  neat - it has the - so I  of my </p>
<p>"Just after the War Neatly of deer were in this section.</p>
<p>"I have a well at my piece, in Ortega, which was dug fifty years ago, and I've been drinking out of it was  It's just about the best water in the world.</p>
<p>"The first artesian well I know of was drilled  house at Mulberry Grove. I do not remember about the date.</p>
<p>"I remember when I was a young boy an old wild  when raised a flock of thirty young ones right in our world.</p>
<p>"The parakeets, young green and yellow birds,  to come in great flocks around Christmas time. They would  in the naberry trees and feast on the clusters of berries  were bare - usually stayings day or so, that  off up the St. Johns River. Some said  around Key most.</p>
<p>"I do not remember every seeing any passenger </p>
<p>"Yes, I remember fishing when the big mullet use to run is schools in the river. One time I caught three  another time we counted seven hundred and ten.</p>
<p>"He, we could not touch a catfish - they were Alligator food. I think that belief was founded on some teaching of the old . I have heard it said - 'Don't out fish without a scale.' But since the preachers preach from the New  it's all right - you can cat frogs, catfish,  rattle</p>
<p> and bread baked over live scale brushes, cat on the ."</p>
<p>Asked if they would accept a treat or a cold drink, both men politely declined; also refused tobacco or cigarettes, but did finally take tip.</p>
<p>"I never  to sacks of the tobacco. For drink Liquor, and I don't  track with </p>
<p>"I remember one time when I was about ten, sure did,  home from the  school - it was  when one of the elder boys  few minutes  the trees .</p>
<p> began to go round  when I finally get t staggered into the house, and my old mummy while, whatever is  and I says,  sick boy." I had already lost my dinner.</p>
<p> throbbing, and  as a loon. Mummy  out and got some big coal leaves oral bound them around  and I get myself to bed, when I finally caught  some around. It was two o'clock the next morning  I was going in live.</p>
<p> a few years later - chow of tobacco, and them  me reel, too. No, I guess me and tobacco just don't mis."</p>
<p>, being more familiar wit, the location of the old Mulberry Grove  asked if us </p>
<p> road build zaring around the old place.</p>
<p>More of the running of the old brick within where the  and carried to the big house further in across  for the river.</p>
<p>"Up on the ridge there are some of the old  hence was off to the right, and the suagr of the slave quarters - the other did  is new. The stable house.</p>
<p>trees were all along  by the river, and  grew in the woods here by the</p>
<p>The other foundation  in the old smokehouse. My Yashor lived up there at Black Point, and after he mother died, some of the have always lived there.</p>
<p>" We will show you the old  Park-Road." (We were  to the highway). been ploughed ever,  the here where the  trucks have been  to Rood's  well, the old Orange Park  ont right along  side of the railroad right-</p>
<p>Years ago we used  all this section  would raise several  a year. It was much  then, and the  would grow tall and tassle, which ot  nowadays, a used to have new sweet potatoes in May.</p>
<p>things grow.  then there was not a  how - the  cut down and there is he </p>
<p>"The smokehouse places was built after the  it was before my time, but I have a brother he remembers it.  Rood Pearson  years elder than he - they  and I have heard Mr. Rood Pearson say he remembers  smokehouse being built when he was little boy.</p>
<p>"I will try to get  to write  we used to sing."</p>
<p>By this time we had reached his small homestead and asked to get out, rather then go on to the  at taken where the interview was began, and was most ready and willing to give any other information decided.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
