<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" rendition="tei:teisimple">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
<p>Rose shepherd</p>
<p>August 25, 1986.</p>
<p>JACKSONVILLE - "Villa Alexandria"</p>
<p>Mrs. Phena Hudnall Love,</p>
<p>216 West Miami Road,</p>
<p>South Jacksonville, Florida.</p>
<p>"Mrs. Alexander Mitchell, (Martha Reed) was the sister of Harrison Reed, Post-War governor of Florida by appointment of a Republic U.S. President, and the widow of Alexander Mitchell, of Milwaukee,  millionaire president of the Illinois Central Railway, and rated as one of the wealthiest men of the West.</p>
<p>"Mrs. Mitchell was a very beautiful woman, charitable in the  of fine character, and not at all in accord with her brother,  who was later impeached and removed from office. She re have anything to do with him and never mentioned his name. Ex-Gov Harrison Reed, died in a little old house at the foot of Flagler- Street in South Jacksonville).</p>
<p>"After the death of Mr. Mitchell, his widow came to Florida, went to California - she always traveled, in a private car and had a of people with her as guests. She lived in Santa Barbara and Los  for a year and a half, trying to decide whether she wished to establish her home there or in Florida. At the end of that period she came to Jacksonville, stopping at the St. James Hotel, then (in the early 70's) ding hostelry, and arranged for the purchase of 125 acres of land on the banks of the St. Johns River on the South Side now near at St. Nicholas place which she called "Villa Alexandria."</p>
<p>"She had plans drawn in Milwaukee for a beautiful home here, and brought down architects, artisans, materials, and erected the mansion on the water's edge.</p>
<p>"Everything was on a very magnificent scale, and it was later  with the most expensive and beautiful furnishings, period furniture from foreign lands, statuary, etc.</p>
<p>"The library was said to have been the finest south of Washington D.C., with original paintings on the walls by old masters, etchings,  hundreds of old volumes, handsomely and expensively bound.</p>
<p>"The linen-room on the second floor was spacious and well  equipped with open racks so that the air could pass through easily,  large room adjoining for the use of the house-keeper.</p>
<p>"After Mrs. Mitchell's death, it fell to my lot to inventory her  and the linen-room was especially interesting. There were dozens sets of matched linens for table use, all elaborately embroidered, with intricate drawn-work, all having her monogram and initials in embroidery, She kepts, two French women busy in Paris, who did  but embroider her household end table linens, and paid them by the year for this work. Royalty never had anything to surpass her possessions in this respect. There were many sets that had never even been unwrapped.</p>
<p>"The draperies were all imported. The bed-rooms were all done inty colors, each equipped with a private bath. Mrs. Mitchell's bed-room was a duplicate of one of the early French Queens - in white  The ceiling was white maple also, panelled with strips of old rose , the canopy and bed drapiers of the some imported material. One nature was a wide bay window overlooking the St. Johns River, which is particularly expansive and beautiful at this point, with curved seats built in, upholstered in the same material, and many lovely cushions. The rugs were all of the oriently imported variety.</p>
<p>"Her commodious dressing room led off from the bed-room, with a sufficient marble bathroom. There was also adjoining, a room floored and paneled with cedar, with closets and drawers, and ample boxes in which were our beautiful dresses and accessories. Mrs. Mitchell had been ill  period before her death, and I found many dresses made by her French dress-maker on previous order, still in their original  and had never been worn.</p>
<p>"The dining-room was octagon shaped, and the mahogany finishing  paneled ceiling, the windows, doors, cabinets/etc, were installed at an estimated  $50,000. The cabinets were filled with the finest of imported that money could buy. This large dining-room seated thirty. Fine  graced the walls, and between the pictures we re silver lighting The floors throughout were of the finest hard-wood variety.</p>
<p>"Alexander and Mrs. Mitchell's only son was John Mitchell, who became a united states senator from winconsin. He had one son, David Mitchell, who made his home at Villa Alexandria, and married Kitty parrott, daughter of an official of the Florida East coast Railway.</p>
<p>"when Kitty Mitchell cams to make her home there, her suite was over all in pure white, with white furniture and all other furnishings.</p>
<p>"The master-bedroom occupied by David was twenty-four feet square, with great mirrors in the dressing room and accommodations for his hundreds suits of clothes. The private bath-room, attached had tiffany glass winters a bath-tub carved out of a solid block of/imported Pyrrean marble, the fittings mounted with ivory and silver. The large washstand also was of the same beautiful marble. There was a square bathing pool, with arrangements made for kish, needle, or shower baths, as desired, reading from this bath-room a medicine closet, completely stocked, a small drug-store in itself.</p>
<p>"The collections of books in the library were beyond description, us were the cabinets that held the beautiful pictures. One box which held pictures portrayed from Holy Script done on parchment - each_</p>
<p> one of the old masters - was priceless. The cabinets were everything strewn around, but I gathered up these belongings tly, dusted than off, and packed them properly numbered and tagged sofa cushions to try to protect them from the dust am improper.</p>
<p>"Kitty Mitchell is father, Mr. Parrott, sold the house to Harry Mason who strapped it of the beautiful furnishings and equipment and  them away.</p>
<p>FUL GROUNDS:</p>
<p>"Mrs. Mitchell also brought landscape gardeners, who terraced grounds and made them a beautiful sight to behold. Flowers, shrubs, plants were brought from all over the world and set out at. There was a stone wall along the bank of the river which tirely covered with Cherokee Roses. The walks were terraced down beautiful boat-house. The upper floor of the boat-house was developed a ball-room with magnificent lounges for both men and women. had a buffet where refreshments, iced-drinks, imported liquors, etc., were . The dock at the landing was large enough and strong enough that steam-boats could land with their loads of invited guests to the affairs which took place there on frequent occasions. Everything has carried out on an extensive, but well appointed scale. The spacious  and gardens were lighted with Japanese lanterns. The tables were  with refreshments.</p>
<p>"When her annual Charity Bazaar took place, Huyler's and other manufacturers would ship down large quantities of candies and other as Contributions for sale, mostly for the benefit of St. Lukee Hospital, of which she was the chief benefactress. She gave thousands of dollars to this institution. At the end of the fiscal year, whatever amount was lacking to cover the operating expenses of the instution, she sent her check to cover. In addition, she supported a lot of people in Jacksonville and Duval County before the days of organized charity, and was a good example of the old adage, "Truly, her left hand knoweth not her right hand doeth."</p>
<p>"Mrs. Mitchell possessed most magnificent jewelry. One set  in particular was of black pearls - ear-rings, necklace and - said to have belonged, to one of the Queens of Europe.</p>
<p>"All in all, the home contained in all probability the most capable and beautiful things that were every brought to Florida, and an inventory which I made for the Court, when the estate was settled, listings of in some instance articles that were almost price-</p>
<p>"Mrs. Mitchell is buried in the old St. Nicholas Cemetery here the South Side."</p>
<p></p>
<p>Mr.  was cen after banking hours in his  in the bend department of the Barnett National Bank. He is  man,  four , rather stockily built  hair and quick-moving gray eyes, and is thirty-five, .</p>
<p> had indu to receive his coat, which a  ever the back of a hear by office chair. He  his coat to the ton of the railing which farced of his  the lobby of the elders section of the bank, and inves to come in and be seated.</p>
<p>"I have been in this position five years, and before this was connecter with the office of Smith-Richardson and , to the hotel supply trade.</p>
<p>"I am  to say I know very little of my great-grand father,  who was a financial power in the late 1860's in his  Wisconsin," said young Alexander Mitchell III. "He  great-grandmother are of English descent and Episcopalians. All family papers have been lost by one means or another and I have nothing to authenticate their arrival and settlement in . However, his financial activation are a matter of record." Production a small paper-bo from the top left-hand crawer  early  quickly to .</p>
<p>"Alexander Mitchell, organizer and first  and stockholder of  Railroad; and  (1869) of the Northwestern National  company.</p>
<p>"I can give no first hand information . For a long time I kept a newspaper clipping of a  the Villa by Harriet Belcher Stowe, but that, too  and I do not know where I could now lay hands  it.</p>
<p>Naturally, I feel rtant in going into as a you  my immediate family. My father and mother  ago: I have always made my home with my mother  know practically nothing of the Mitchell family history.</p>
<p>"My father David Mitchell I have not seen for considerably ever a  if he is at present in Jacksonville. However Mr. bridge Richardson, Mr. Francis P. Floming, Mr. J. Y. Wilson,  to give some club as to his whereabouts."</p>
<p> hands played nervously with a pencil, and he evidently anxious to get back to the compilation of his report.</p>
<p>"No, I do not know if I will ever attain to any suck reputation as my famous ancestor enjoyed in the financial world, but I am glad to have become associated with the oldest banking intion in Jacksonville, and I an ostly trying to make good just as if I were the first Mitchell in the country, with no anstral ground or achievement to live up to.</p>
<p>"A banker's life is not a bad of roses - it means long and hard work, just the come as any other vocation, with the  of responsibility for other people's finances. When  down at the  at 2 p.m.  the doors are closed,  hours  for the employees; sometimes it  afternoon like  with  cream for into the night during special rushes or busy seasons.</p>
<p>"I could not discuss my work, that would have to come from the  of my department." he said, clipping his sentences with the  of dismissal.</p>
<p>"Always work? Well, I have a little recreation. I  of swimming and I have just taken up golf - but I don't  I'll ever become a 'bug' about that. Not so much time to .</p>
<p>"My early teachers were in a private school, then I attended the Duval County public schools, later  from the University of Florida. Now, I an studying a special course in  by the American Institute of Banking, and other things in  to my work, that takes up a great many of my off hours.</p>
<p>"Vote? Yes I vote, as a matter of course, but I am  I never make a ward politician." he laughed - "too many creeks and turns. Nationally, I like President Roosevelt's  believe in time will get finances, labor, and living  of the American people on the up-and-up."</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
