<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" rendition="tei:teisimple">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Federal Writers Project</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
<p>Socie-Etinic Study</p>
<p>The Crooks in America</p>
<p>Cora Lee Taylor</p>
<p>February 5, 1940</p>
<p>Mabel B. Francis Editor</p>
<p>Miami, Florida.</p>
<p>NICHOLAS P. PET</p>
<p>134 Northeast Second Avenue</p>
<p>Miami, Florida</p>
<p>Master Nicholas Papa Petron, age 40, is a hale appearing man with a ruddy complexion, dark hair and very bright dark open. His neat grooming and his happy, anger, confident expression distinguish him as a person of unusual intelligence and refinement.</p>
<p>Master Papa Petron conducts a church school for the Greek children from four to six  afternoon during the regular school year. The school is supported by the church, and although no distinct religious training is given, many moral lessons are taught in the reading classes through the simple stories in the text books. The aim of the school is to teach the pupils to read and write the Greek language as mental discipline, to  it  for them to learn other for language as in high school, to aid them to secure positions where interpreters are needed, and to keep the children interested in the Greek church through their ability to understand the services.</p>
<p>The text books are a ranged like American school readers with short stories and bright pictures of American children, games, and pots. The stories teach good health habits, such as thing, brushing the tooth, taking proper sleep and exercise, also kindness to animals and playmates, abandoned to parents and habits of truthfulness.</p>
<p>Mr. Petron explained: "I very  use my titles when signing my , except on my passports.  the title of Factor when I graduated from Normal school in Cyprus. My title, Papa was my birthday  by the Greek Orthodox  because I am the son of riest. My father having  ried before taking the  of priesthood at , Cyprus. This , which  orally observed by my church, is the all of point of difference between the Greek Orthodox and the  Catholic .</p>
<p>"Except in the schoolroom where I am called Taster." I am usually called 'Papa Petron' and I usually,  my name,  P. Petron."</p>
<p>"My father was a teacher and I had all the advantages of getting a good education. I finished school at an early age and then was seat to boarding school. My masters were appointed by the English Government. The English language was never difficult for me. I love it, only I find that I haven't a fluent tongue to speak it. I've studied for 15 years, but I still need a special teacher to help no express myself better. Our school was a very high-class school. We had to high a paper that we didn't dance, didn't drink a smoke and didn't do any of those things. Couldn't have stayed there, if we didn't leave (live) clean lives. If I didn't, the children would read it on me.</p>
<p>"After I applied to the consul for  to come to America. I had to wait three cars  I was notified. My consul bought my ticket and told me just what to do.  no trouble  ever  position as teacher had hour, secured by the ch in Roanoke. Virginia. I was paid for my teaching and loading the choice.</p>
<p>"I thought I have the English language very well, bat I had , of trouble getting read to the American language, for I had only British English teacher. One of the first things I discovered was that Americans do not talk like my teachers talked, so I was afraid to use my English at first. I always carried with me  dictionary in my pocket and I made good use of it. My annual did not tell me how to get to R from now . I hated to ask anyone for fear they would think me very ignorant.</p>
<p>"I went to the station with my language, but what to do, I did not know. I stood there and  and there I saw some letters staring at  I  to myself that word is in-for-ma-tion! What that word information could means I couldn't  off it. I use fallen go to that  I looked in my dictionary and  was like a friend to help me. They told me where to buy my ticket and I thought I had all the information I needed.</p>
<p>"I brought my ticket and understand the  to tell me that the train would come at 10  o'clock (10:30). I tl that was what  what 10 o'clock , but I couldn't thing what 10 could noun. I couldn't find it in my dictionary.</p>
<p>"Ha! Ha! It is funny now when I think of it! Wall, I just sat there. I  I'd ask  trading came in, if it would take me to  o'clock came but no train and oh, it seemed an long to wait until 10 hearty! </p>
<p>"I had the correct address of where I was  in Roano, but I had no idea how I was going to find it.</p>
<p>I had read about the English Bobbies, so I thought I'd know a poli, I'll saw one. Sure enough! I stopped up to a man in uniform and told him  I  to go.</p>
<p> don't  take a taxing to asked.</p>
<p>"Taxi! Taxi! I wondered "what's that."  before I had the to look in my dictionary, I  a driver calling:</p>
<p>" this way for a taxi!"</p>
<p>" a cub and reached by domination at last.</p>
<p>", I  to find a resti have me a  card, I should see that it was printed in English bat I was afraid to try to say the words in a office, and besides there were so many words that I didn't know what they meant and I didn't want to take out my dictionary there before the waiter. So I just gave a quick  at the noun and said:</p>
<p>"Human'!" (ham and eggs), "I didn't know what that was, but I renumbered of hearing a  and in How York that he went to a restaurant and made a  of  So I thought if he could out it  it was. I could eat it once anyway.</p>
<p>"All the  I was waiting I was wondering what is this that I ordered and I almost I  they brought me afga kroas. ( Xorine, (Zereno, of pig; kroas, meat. I sat there thinking:</p>
<p>"Before you come to America you studied English, French and Latin. You graduated from boarding school in Creek and no you have a hard time learning American. It is so different from British English. Well, anyway I didn't  a big break that time.</p>
<p>"Another time, I wanted a glass of milk. An I had been taught that it is more polite to speak in sentences, I asked:</p>
<p>"Hav 'you ' The waitress couldn't rutand me. I repeated ever and ever as planning as I could: 'Hav' you :' Finally she asked: 'What do you want?' O said: 'Moolk' She Laughed:</p>
<p>'I get yuh.' We get ' Then everybody laughed.</p>
<p>"My oh!" I thought, "that sounds like the  word for God.</p>
<p>"I didn't  she was two ring or  I asked a friend afterwards what she  in America.  'You don't tall. American you talk British English. You must it say , say . You See, I had  book taught to .</p>
<p>"I went  Cypress in 1935-54 to fining in normal training. Then I  my English degree pof Laster rich means . You say '' and  of teacher ever .</p>
<p>"When I came back, I stared in New York. For a little while and applied for a position as interpreter. They opened the book of , pointed to four lines and said: 'See if you  slate these Four lines.' 'I can't do that, but I'll login at the first  translate the whole book for you. I have tight that book and know every word. Then they, said. 'you'll do.'</p>
<p>From , Virginia, I went from ones late to another actually staying a year at a place, so before coming here I had taught in New Bedford,  and Watertown, Nassashasotts Forward. New Jersey, and Columbus, Ohio. I have book here since , but it is hard to tell here I'll be next . I like it in better that my place I've been.</p>
<p>"I've traveled quite a bit in  Italy, France,  the . Lived America. I went to school, connection to high school and  times to night school. Once I taught la. I am about ready  my second papers new.</p>
<p>"My mother an  are living  my three - all married. We  system of as  crore. If we think  girl we are introduced , but we do  court for until we speak to both  other and the . He says: 'Would you like to have me for your son.' Then they ask all kinds of tions to find out if we have the characteristics they want their son to have and  they are satisfied, they say: 'Alright.'</p>
<p>"Of course, I studied my theology,  my parents impressed on e that only  people  of the myths. So nothing happened to me that made we believe in the  school was a good school. You did not teach they, used t teach 200 years are when they tried to rule by fear. I never  I never had to which my pupils, only to say: 'Don't do that say.'  was all I needed to say."</p>
<p>He showed  English text book that he studied in Cyprus, He known every page by eart. It is a rather quaint English grammar explaining the parts of speech and sentence ction, and covering 96 pages. Many of the sentences are rather depression, as follow:</p>
<p>"To help the poor  became his chief ."</p>
<p>"To stock  by the </p>
<p>For he felt that his soul was  its .</p>
<p>And his  could hear him  and cry</p>
<p> to have told her that wacked lie."</p>
<p>" broke the cap."</p>
<p>Lose dog  him?"</p>
<p>"The boy beat the man in a game of checkers."</p>
<p>"The healthy pity the sick."</p>
<p>"Anger drove him will."</p>
<p>"The fight struck him with horror."</p>
<p>"He cannot tell what caused his fall."</p>
<p>"And kind cheered his drooping soul</p>
<p>And slowly  his languid cheek.</p>
<p>The big round tears were seen to roll,</p>
<p>It told the things he could not speak."</p>
<p>The Look  repeated many  and previous, quotations from  and  follow.</p>
<p>"Judor a screeching  tree</p>
<p>The village  stands."</p>
<p>"A Switch in  saves nine."</p>
<p>"To do to others as I would</p>
<p>That the  do to me</p>
<p>Will  honest, kind and, you</p>
<p>An  to be.</p>
<p>"People  in glass  should he threw ."</p>
<p>"To speak a little less think we  is we ."</p>
<p>The title page follows:</p>
<p>The Primary Grammar</p>
<p>An  of the  for use of pupil in  primary schools.</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>R.R. Smithurd</p>
<p>Principal higher Schools of America</p>
<p>Cairo, Egypt.</p>
<p>London</p>
<p>George Phillies and Son, Ltd.</p>
<p>32  Street</p>
<p>19.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
